Well, that was not an easy quiz.
这并不是一个简单的小测验
To show you the answer, what we're going to do is we're
为呈现答案 接下来我们要做的就是
going to calculate all these three equations,
计算这三个方程式
x plus y, x times y,
x+y xy
and x squared plus y squared,
和 x²+y²
at each one of the eight points.
代入全部 8 个点的坐标
So, here we have our eight points.
这里我们有 8 个点
Minus 3 minus 3, 3 minus 3,
(-3,-3)、(3,-3)
etc., all the way to 1,1.
一直到 (1,1)
And the first four are red,
前四个是红色的
and the last four are blue.
后四个是蓝色
So, let's calculate x plus y.
我们先来计算 x+y
At the first point, minus 3 minus 3 is the sum of two coordinates, which is minus 6.
第一个点 -3 加 -3 是两个坐标之和 等于 -6
For the second one, it's 3 minus 3 which is 0,
第二个点是 3 加 -3 等于0
and all the way to 1 plus 1, which is two.
最后到 1 加 1 等于 2
And let's see what happens to these values in the number line.
让我们看看在数轴会发生什么
The blue points are mapped at 0, 2 and,
蓝点标在 0 2 和 -2
minus 2, and the red points are mapped at 0,6 and minus 6.
红点标在 0 6 和 -6
There's still no clear cut,
这里的分割仍旧不是很清晰
no place where we can cut this number line that
这里我们无法切出一条线
will separate the red points from the blue points.
来分开红点和蓝点
And this is something we could have guessed before because x plus y is a linear equation,
这印证了我们之前的猜想 因为 x+y 是一个线性方程
and we've established in the previous video,
在我们之前的视频中已经提过
that linear equations do not separate these points.
线性方程无法分开这些点
And therefore, a line won't be able to cut these data.
因此 一条线是无法分开这些数据的
So let's try with the next one,
我们试试下一个
x times y, which is not linear, so, there is a hope.
xy 这不是线性的 还有点可能
So x times y has the following values,
xy 有下面的一些数值
minus 3 times minus 3 is nine,
-3 乘以 3 等于 9
3 times minus 3 is minus 9, etc., etc.,
3 乘以 -3 等于 -9 等等
all the way to 1 times 1 equals 1.
直到 1 乘以 1 等于 1
And we plot these points on the line,
我们在数轴上绘制这些点
and the blue points go to 1 and minus 1,
蓝点是 1 和 -1
and the red points go at 9 and minus 9 so there is still no separation.
红点是 9 和 -9 仍然无法分开这些点
There's no way to cut this number line in two,
我们仍旧无法以此方式
in such a way that the red points are on one side,
将数轴一分为二 使红点在一侧
and the blue points are on the other side.
蓝点在另一侧
So, xy won't work either.
所以 xy 同样也失败
Now, let's try with x squared plus y squared.
那我们来试试 x²+y²
At minus 3 minus 3,
在 (-3 -3)
we get minus 3 squared plus minus 3 squared, which is 18,
我们得到 -3 平方加 -3 平方 等于 18
and all the other values are 18,18,18,
所有其他数值也都是 18
and then two for the blue ones,
蓝色的两个
since 1 squared plus 1 squared is equal to two.
鉴于 1 平方加 1 平方等于 2
So, in our number line,
那在数轴上
all the blue points cluster at two,
所以蓝点集都在 2
and the red points cluster at 18.
红点集都是 18
And now, we can cut the number line in two,
现在 我们可以将数轴一分为二
because if we draw a vertical line at 10.
因为如果我们在 10 的地方画一条垂线
It can really be anywhere,
这条线可以在任何一个地方
but the best cut is at the middle, which is 10.
但最佳之处在中间 也就是 10
Then we've managed to separate the points.
这样我们就可以分开这些点了
So x squared plus y squared is the function that wins.
因此 x²+y² 这方法可行
And so, basically, what we have is that for the blue points,
基本上对于蓝点来说
x squared plus y squared equals two,
x²+y² 等于2
and for the red points, x squared plus y squared equals 18.
对于红点来说 x²+y² 等于 18
And how do you split it at two and 18?
那你怎么分开 2 和 18 呢
Well, let's say with the 10 that goes right in the middle.
两者的中间就是 10
So, our magic equation is x squared plus y squared equals 10,
所以我们这个神奇的方程式就是 x²+y²=10
and let's remember that equation.
记住这个方程式
Now, we go to the circle.
现在我们画个圆
And what do you think the equation of this circle is?
你们认为这个圆的方程是什么
Well, x squared plus y squared is equal to 10.
对 就是 x²+y²=10
That is the circle that separates the red points from the blue points.
这就是分开红点和蓝点的圆
But now, let's go back to the building methods,
现在让我们回到建楼法
since I promised that the circle method and the building method were the same.
之前我说过 圆形法和建楼法是一样的
So, here, I'll show you why.
现在我来讲为什么
Let's recall that on the left,
我们还记得左边的这个图
we have a flat world, and on the right,
是一个平面 右边的图
we have a three-dimensional world,
是一个三维空间
which is a building with many floors.
也就是一栋有许多层的楼
And our new axis is z.
然后我们引入 z 轴
And our floors are at z equals 18,
我们的楼层在 z 等于 18 处 也就是就是第 18 层
the 18th floor and at z equals to the second floor.
以及 z 等于 2 处 也就是第 2 层
And the blue points are in the second floor,
蓝点位于 2 层
and the red points are in the 18th floor.
红点位于 18 层
So, how do we separate them?
我们如何划分呢？
Well, by putting a separator plane in the middle, say in the 10th floor.
通过在中间放一个水平面 即 10 层
And that's what the SVM does in three-dimensions.
这就是支持向量机在 3D 空间里发挥的作用
It drafts the best separating plane with the algorithm that we've learned previously.
它绘制出了我们之前学过的最理想的分割面
But now, how do we get a circle out of this?
但现在 我们如何从中得到一个圆呢?
Well, if we consider the function z equals x squared,
让我们来想想方程式 z=x²+y²
plus y squared, that's this paraboloid.
也就是这个抛物面
And this paraboloid intersects each one of the planes at a circle.
这个抛物面与每个平面相交得出一个圆
The circle in the bottom contains the four blue points,
底部的圆包括 4 个蓝点
and the one in the top contains the four red points.
顶部的圆包括 4 个红点
And the circle in the middle plane actually goes here,
中间水平面的圆在这里
and it has equation, you guessed it,
它有一个等式 没错
x squared plus y squared equals 10,
就是 x²+y²=10
since both of these values are z.
因为它们都是 z 的值
So, that's why the circle and the building method are the same,
所以 这就是为什么圆形法和建楼法是一样的
and they're both the kernel method for SVMs.
它们都是支持向量机的核函数
So, here's a summary of what's happening.
我们来进行一个总结
Let's say we're in a two-dimensional world,
假设在一个二维世界里
and let's say we have a set of points that cannot be separated linearly.
我们有一组点 无法被线性分开
So, we embed our dataset into a five dimensional world by taking the point xy,
我们把数据嵌入到一个五维世界中 取点 (x,y)
and sending it to the point x comma y comma x squared comma xy comma y squared.
在五维中 坐标变为 (x,y,x²,xy,y²)
As a small example, the point 2,3 will be sent to the point 2, 3,4, 6, 9.
举个例子 点 (2,3) 就会变成 (2,3,4,6,9)
Now, the data lives in higher dimensions,
现在 数据处于一个更高维度中
and maybe we're lucky that in here,
也许我们在这里很幸运
we can actually separate it with a four-dimensional hyperplane.
我们可以把它分为一个四维超平面
Well, now, we go back and project that to
现在 让我们回去
the two-dimensional world and we get a polynomial of degree two,
回到二维世界中 得到一个二次多项式
which will nicely separate our data.
这将会很好的分割我们的数据
This is called a polynomial kernel.
这被称作是多项式核函数
And a kernel really means a set of functions that will come to help us out.
一个核函数就意味着可以帮助我们解决问题的一组函数
So, to show this is a similar dataset twice.
我们再来看看这两个相似的数据集
And if we use a linear kernel,
如果我们使用线性核函数
that's like a bag with tools,
就好像一个包里有很多工具
and our tools are the variable x and variable y.
我们的工具就是变量 x 和变量 y
And we're looking at all the functions that we can build
我们在寻找任何关于这两个变量的线性组合方程式
this linear combinations of these two variables so we can create, for example,
因此 我们就可以创建 比如
2x minus y equals 1,
2x-y=1
or 5x minus 2y equals three,
或者 5x-2y=3
or x plus y equals 4.
或者 x+y=4
Basically any line. But, if we extend it to a polynomial kernel,
几乎就是任何一条线了 但是如果我们把它扩展为一个多项式核函数
now we have the following tools.,
我们就有以下的工具
We still have x and y but now,
我们还是有 x 和 y
we also have x squared,
我们也有 x²
xy, and y squared.
xy 和 y²
This gives us a lot more room to build functions to separate the data.
这给了我们很大空间来建立函数分割数据
So now we can construct circles such as x squared plus y squared equals
所以现在我们可以建立圆的方程 比如 x²+y²=1
one or hyperbolas such as x times y equals one.
或者双曲线 xy=1
And here, I only drew half of the hyperbola, but that's okay.
这里我只画了双曲线的一半 没关系的
We can construct parabolas like this one at y equals x squared,
我们还可以建立 y=x² 这样的抛物线
and in general, we can create a lot more functions and build a lot more boundaries.
大体来说 我们可以创建更多方程式 建立更多边界
And the algorithm is exactly as before.
而算法则和之前一样
We just add some dimensions to the data,
我们在数据上增加一些维度
find a higher dimensional surface,
寻找一个更高维度的表面
project it down, and we get our curves.
投射到平面上形成曲线
And if we have even higher degree polynomials like these, well,
如果我们有这种更高次数的多项式
we can create them with a polynomial kernel of a higher degree,
我们也可以创建更高次数的多项式核函数
say three, which has all these degree three monomials as well.
比如 3 次 就可以利用这些三次单项式
And, in general, the degree of a polynomial kernel is
总之 多项式核函数就是一个超参数
a hyperparameter that we can train to find the best possible model.
我们可以通过训练它找到可能的最佳模型